Guess I’ll play dumb.
That’s right.
He seems to like Gon,
so he might help us.
-[Gon] Hey!
-[Killua] You idiot!
Oh, yeah! Oops…
What?
Do you know someone here?
Uh… no…
Hey!
It’s that girl we met!
[Phinks] Is that true, Shizuku?
You know these guys?
No. I sure don’t.
[Killua] Huh?
[Feitan] Oh… I remember now.
The kid who arm wrestles.
Refresh my memory.
That kid.
You lost to him
in an arm-wrestling contest two days ago.
I did? He beat me?
That’s a lie!
I’m not the strongest,
but I wouldn’t lose to a kid…
Well...
It’s because you were using
your right hand.
I did? But why? I’m left handed.
[Feitan] Don't bother.
Once she has forgotten something,
it is gone for good.
Right. Never mind, guess I was mistaken.
Thought so.
Hold on. Is that right?
You really beat Shizuku?
Yeah.
I never would have imagined
that she was a Phantom Troupe member.
Okay. Then show me what you’ve got.
[theme song playing]
ALLY x AND x SWORD
[Nobunaga] One more time.
Ready…
Go.
[straining]
All right, one more time.
Ready…
Go.
[straining]
So...
How do I stack up
against all the other Spiders?
Be honest.
Probably seventh or eighth, I’d guess.
Well you aren’t the weakest
but not the strongest, either.
Right.
The strongest member of the Troupe
was this guy called Uvogin.
But it’s starting to look like
the chain user killed him.
We told you!
We have no clue who that is!
[Nobunaga] Hey, kid!
Speak without my permission again…
and I’ll kill you.
Now, one more time.
Ready…
Go.
Uvogin was an Enhancer.
He was simple-minded, straightforward,
and he loved a good fight.
And punctual.
A real stickler about time.
Whenever Franklin or I were late,
he’d always start something.
He beat the crap out of me
more than once, I can tell ya!
I’ve known him since
before the Troupe was founded.
I know him better than anyone.
He would never...
I mean never
lose in a fair fight, do you hear me?
Not unless he was caught
in some dirty trap!
I’ll make his killer pay.
I’ll find him,
no matter who I have to kill.
The chain user holds
some kind of grudge against us -
a strong one.
The Mafia’s Nostrade family
hired him recently.
[Killua] A grudge against the Troupe…
A recent hire? [gasps]
You may not know him personally
but maybe you heard rumors…
So, think hard, all right?
You’d better not hold anything back!
I don’t know him.
But even if I did,
I would still never give him up to you!
I thought you were all
a bunch of cold-blooded monsters
but I see you can shed tears
for your friends.
So, you’re capable of empathy.
But you’ve killed...
you’ve killed so many people!
Why couldn’t you feel that for them?
[yells] What the hell is wrong with you?!
[seething]
Careful. You’re too cocky.
[grunt of pain]
Gon!
Move and I’ll cut you.
[Feitan] Answer the question.
Do you know who the chain user is?
I told you!
I’m not telling you anything,
so get off me!
[Feitan smirks]
[Nobunaga] Feitan.
Stop it.
[Feitan] Stop what?
Stop doing what you’re just about to do.
[Feitan] Oh? You think you know
what I’m about to do?
You’re going to break his arm, aren’t you?
I’d start with a finger…
peel off a nail.
Doesn’t matter.
I told you to stop it!
You’re giving me orders?
I don’t have to obey.
Hey, quit it, Nobunaga.
What, have you
already forgotten the rules?
There’s no physical fighting
between the Troupe members.
I know, I know.
Disputes are decided by a coin toss.
[Feitan] Tails.
[Nobunaga] Then I’m heads.
It’s heads.
So, let him go.
[Shizuku] Well, what do we do with them?
They haven’t told us
anything about the chain user.
If they don’t know anything,
then just let ‘em go.
Am I right, Pakunoda?
[Pakunoda] I checked on the trip here.
It’s true.
They really don’t know anything.
-[Machi] You sure?
-I am.
They have no memories
of the chain user whatsoever.
Looks like your hunch
was a little off this time, huh?
That’s bizarre…
Oh well. If Pakunoda says so,
it must be true.
Hey, Gon.
Did they do anything to you
on the way here?
Not really. Just asked me some questions.
Thought so.
[Killua] So she examined us
without us knowing.
What was it?
And how?
It sounds like
they all have a lot of faith
in that Pakunoda woman’s
judgment.
Her skill must be
more accurate than instinct.
[Pakunoda] They have no memories
of the chain user whatsoever.
[Killua] Memories?
How about you?
Have any guesses?
[Killua] The power
to scan someone’s memory!
By what, touching them?
That would explain everything.
We’re in big trouble.
When she scanned us before,
I had no idea who the chain user was.
But now…
I have an image in my head.
If she checks again...
[Franklin] They don’t know the chain user.
so can’t we just let them go now?
[Shalnark] Yeah. I really don’t see
the point in keeping them here.
[Phinks] No. We can’t be sure
they’re completely unrelated.
It’s possible they’re being used.
The chain user is discreet.
He usually keeps his chains hidden.
If that’s the case,
maybe they don’t realize he’s
who we’re talking about.
We shouldn’t release them.
Not until they tell us
who they’re working for.
If they are working for someone,
then it isn’t the chain user.
Because he prefers
to operate all by himself.
[Machi] So, you’re saying
you agree with Nobunaga?
We can get whatever information we need
from the Nostrade family.
We don’t really need these kids for that.
After all…
we know the chain user is a member.
That’s right, we do.
Our only target right now
is the chain user,
so we can pretty much ignore
everybody else.
[Feitan] There you go.
You are lucky.
[Nobunaga] Not just yet.
I’m not letting the kid go.
You wanna join the Spiders?
Team up with me.
No.
I would rather die
than team up with you guys!
So, it’s never gonna happen!
[laughing]
He really hates us, doesn’t he?
What are you?
You’re an Enhancer, right?
Yeah, and what if I am?
I thought you’d say that.
[chuckling]
[laughter]
[Nobunaga] Hey!
We’re keeping them here
until the Boss gets back.
I’m nominating him.
Are you serious?
[Feitan] The Boss will never agree
to that.
[Machi] Fine, whatever.
But you’ve gotta babysit ‘em.
It’s on you if they escape.
[Shizuku] Really? He reminds you of Uvo?
Yeah. He wears all his emotions
right on his sleeve.
And when he’s mad,
he forgets about the consequences.
But what’s the most like Uvo,
is he’s at his absolute strongest
when he’s fighting for someone else.
He liked to fight alone
but Uvo was never more powerful
than when he would go off
and team up with Nobunaga
to fight an entire horde.
He never admitted it,
but I think Uvo preferred
having someone there to protect.
[Shizuku] He was stronger
when someone was holding him back?
[Franklin] I guess you could say that…
[Feitan] She does not mince words,
does she?
On the other hand,
Nobunaga’s skills
are excellent for dueling.
You might even say
that they’re only effective one-on-one.
Whenever those two had to fight together,
they would always complain.
But I’m pretty sure they both enjoyed it.
[Shalnark] Okay. Enough reminiscing.
Let’s get down to business.
Here’s a full list
of the Nostrade family members.
I got it straight
from the official Hunter website.
These five are especially important.
They serve as full time bodyguards
for the Boss’s daughter.
Not to mention the fact
that they’re the ones who captured Uvo.
But Uvo was certain
that the chain user wasn’t on this list.
And since we have no idea
what he looks like,
we’re going to need
to find someone who does.
Hey. That’s the guy I killed.
The one on the top left.
You can cross him off.
[Shalnark] All right pair up
and search the area.
And keep a sharp eye out
for any of the people
that are on this list.
We’ll all meet back here at ten p.m.
Got it? Let’s move.
[Machi] Hey, hold on!
Nobunaga’s staying here, right?
What about me?
You can just team up with whoever is left.
[light chuckle]
[resigned sigh]
Ow…
[Killua] That was stupid of me…
If I’d made a move,
Hisoka would’ve killed me
without a second thought.
That murderous aura…
I was paralyzed.
If they’d threatened to kill Gon,
would I have been able to stop them?
Would I have even been able to move?
[Illumi] You can’t do it, can you?
Because deep down inside,
you’re more worried about
whether you can defeat me
than anything else.
[Killua] You’re wrong!!
Remember the lesson I drilled into you?
Never go up against a superior opponent.
No, you’re wrong!
[scoffs] Pretty scary.
If looks could kill, huh?
I should warn you…
Step into range and I’ll cut you down.
Killua!
[Killua - shallow breathing]
[Killua] I don’t stand a chance
against him.
I’ve gotta think of a way to escape…
No windows…
and only one exit.
How are we supposed to get him
to move away from the door?
Hey, I wonder if Leorio is okay.
I really hope he was able
to get a hold of Mister Zepile…
Killua? You okay?
Yeah.
Let’s see……
Mister Zepile taught us cauterization,
autopsy and something else.
Remember what it was?
I forgot.
Was it osmosis, maybe?
I don’t think it was,
but I just don’t know…
[Killua] Gon.
I’ll be the decoy.
Wait for it
and then try to escape.
What are you talking about?
[Nobunaga] Look, seriously…
forget all about it.
You’re good enough to recognize
the difference in our abilities.
You won’t catch me off guard.
I know that already!
This room has one exit
and nowhere to hide.
He can see everything we’re doing.
He can even keep an eye on us
without ever creating an opening.
He’s probably an Iaido master,
and with his shodachi,
his range is twice mine.
One step too close
and I’m dead meat.
But that’s what gives it meaning!
[Illumi] You can’t do it, can you?
Shut up, all right?!
The only way I’ll find out is if I try!
Killua, what are you thinking about doing?
[Killua] I’ll stop his shodachi,
even if it kills me.
When I do,
you run away!
[Gon angered grunt]
Huh?
[yells] What the hell was that for, huh?!
-Stop being so selfish!
-Huh?
Don’t talk about dying
like it’s no big deal?!
Why not? You did!
You said the same thing earlier!
I’m allowed to!
But you’re not, do you hear me?!
Huh?
[Nobunaga laughing]
Reason never works on an Enhancer.
I thought you knew that, kid!
We can’t escape
unless we’re prepared to die,
you stupid little jerk!
You don’t know what I was thinking!
So, tell me, who’s the selfish one now?!
No! I don’t know!
‘Cause I’m stupid!
[hearty laughter]
You two kids are hilarious, you know that?
Listen I’m not gonna hurt you.
Just behave yourselves.
I know you guys mean business, all right?
Don’t throw your lives away.
Sit tight and wait
until the Boss gets back.
And if you don’t strike his fancy,
you get to leave, free and clear.
But try to escape and I’ll kill you.
Make me draw my sword from its scabbard
and you won’t survive to talk about it.
[Gon] Oh!
I remember now!
The other one is ostomy!
Cauterization, autopsy…
and the last one’s ostomy!
Do you remember now?
Yeah! I just wish
I’d thought of it sooner!
Right?
I can’t believe we both
forgot something so simple!
What?
Now that we’ve figured that out…
Let's go!
Are you serious?
You know you’re going to die.
I’m not nearly skilled or merciful enough
to temper my strength to face you.
You fools!
[Gon] If the exit is blocked…
[Killua] ...you’ve just gotta
make your own!
[Nobunaga] The wall…
Which one do I chase?
We’re on the fifth floor.
The cat-eyed kid’s already by the stairs.
So, the black-haired kid!
There. Now he doesn’t have
anywhere to run.
What am I thinking?
They can keep
breaking through walls to escape!
The cat-eyed kid is below.
I’ll stay on the black-haired one.
Where is he?
The walls are intact.
So’s the door.
Killua! Are you there?
[Killua] Yeah! I’m here!
That’s it!
Then that must mean the last hole…
was a decoy!
He busted the wall,
then doubled back and hid
in the next room, so I’d pass him!
We can beat him. The two of us!
His presence disappeared.
Zetsu?
Does this idiot really want to fight me?
An advanced application of Ten and Ren…
En!
Aura envelops the body
in a layer a few millimeters
to a couple centimeters thick.
But with En, you can extend it
as far as necessary.
You can sense anyone who enters your En.
Inside it you can even count the leaves
as they fall.
You can conceal your presence
before your approach,
never making a sound.
But enter my En and my sword flies.
Come. I’m ready.
[Killua] That idiot.
Man. I really wanted to beat that guy up.
Yeah, fat chance of that.
He’d kill you twice before you tried.
[Gon] You sure about that?
[Killua] We only know the basics of Nen.
We wouldn’t stand a chance.
[chuckles]
What’s so funny?
You’re back to being your old self again!
It’s my job to be reckless…
and it’s your job to stay cool
and keep me in line!
[light derisive snort]
Glad I can count on ya, pal!
You’re being selfish!
[Gon] Well? What do we do next?
[Killua] Depends on what
we wanna do, I guess.
Okay. I wanna kick their butts!
Figured.
Well, that’s not too different
from the original plan.
But both of us’ll need to improve our Nen,
if that’s what we decide we’re gonna do.
There’s only one way we might get
as strong as we’ll need to
and that’s Nen.
And the fastest way
is through Kurapika.
We need to go ask him.
[Gon] Huh? Why?
[Killua] Because he’s the “chain user”
who defeated their friend
and got us into this mess.
[Gon] What?
[Killua] Wait, you hadn’t figured
that out yet?
[Gon] You really think it’s Kurapika?
I’m pretty sure it is.
And if I’m right,
we still have a chance.
You and I both started learning Nen
at around the same time Kurapika did.
What we need to do now
is learn the unique abilities
that fit our talents.
But what’s even more important…
we’ve got to gain the strength
we’ll need to face the Phantom Troupe.
And you really think Kurapika’s the key
to finding the answers we’re looking for?
Yeah.
[narrator] Meanwhile, deep in
the troubled heart of Yorknew City
a fearsome storm has begun to brew.
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Coming up:
-Gon...
-[Killua] ...and Killua’s…
[both] Hunterpedia!
-I’m Gon!
-I’m Killua!
[both] And this is our Hunterpedia!
Today, we’ll introduce Franklin.
He’s an Emitter
and a Phantom Troupe member!
His Double Machine Gun attack
shoots Nen bullets.
Use your fingers as guns
for an extra punch!
Pew, pew, pew!
[Gon] Next time:
"A x Brutal x Battlefield."
-Out.
-[Killua] Out?
[Gon] Outfield!
[Gon and Killua] Infield!